Guide to the Walter Bedell Smith Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Walter Bedell Smith papers
1949-1950
MS 388
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
Correspondence and writings of Walter Bedell Smith, relating to My Three Years in Moscow, a book published in 1950.
Smith, Walter Bedell, 1895-1961
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Born in Indianapolis, Indiana, October 5, 1895, Walter Bedell Smith graduated from various military schools before graduating from Army War College in 1937. He was an army officer from 1910 to 1945, becoming major general in 1945 and later, general. He served with General Staff Corps in 1940 and was secretary for the U.S. Combined Chiefs of Staff and U.S. Joint Chiefs of Staff in 1941 and 1942. He was Chief of Staff for the Allied Force Headquarters in North Africa between 1942 and 1944. Between 1946 and 1949, he served as U.S. ambassador to the U.S.S.R. He was then director of the Central Intelligence Agency between 1950 and 1953, then becoming Undersecretary of State until 1954. He was also a member of the boards of several corporations. Smith died on August 9, 1961, and is buried at Arlington National Cemetery.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence and writings of Walter Bedell Smith, relating to My Three Years in Moscow, a book published in 1950.
Soviet Union -- Description and travel; United States -- Foreign relations; United States -- Officials and employees in foreign countries; Diplomats; Smith, Walter Bedell, 1895-1961; United States. Department of State
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  All of the papers, with the exception of some of the miscellaneous correspondence, concern Walter Bedell Smith's book, My Three Years in Moscow (published in 1950). He seems to have organized his material into twelve chapters and twelve "articles," before its final arrangement in fifteen chapters.
  - Correspondence with the Department of State relating to clearance for publication, 1949 August-November (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, and list of Army officers, 1949 July-Dec, 1950 September (Box 1)
  - [Early notes and drafts] (Box 1)
  - Audiograph dictating discs, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Typed notes with MS corrections, some transcribed with dictating discs, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Typed notes with MS corrections: miscellaneous numbered drafts, 1949 (Box 1)
  - [First complete draft?] (Box 1)
  - Chapters I-XII: corrected typescript, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Articles: manuscripts, typescripts, and research material for quotations [some of this series may be out of order], 1949 (Box 2)
  - Introductory material, Articles I-VIII, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Articles IX-XII, 1949 (Box 3)
  - [Final draft?]: typescript (Box 3)
  - Chapters I-XII (2 copies), 1949 (Box 3)
  - Articles I-VII, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Articles VIII-XII, 1949 (Box 4)